# **Cassie Simpson**

Phone: (320) 212-1654 | Email: cassie.s.simpson@gmail.com | Chaska, MN, 55318

LinkedIn: bit.lv/3CduTZK | Portfolio: bit.lv/3718aEz | GitHub: bit.lv/3sNpiGt

#### **Summary**

Front-end web developer with 4 years of IT experience and skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Minnesota Coding Boot Camp. Known as an efficient problem-solver who is passionate about developing accessible, mobile-first, engaging applications that clearly communicate with visitors. Strengths include creativity, teamwork, and high technical aptitude.

#### **Technical Skills**

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, GitHub, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

### **Projects**

Weather Dashboard | Github: bit.ly/3tryBL5 | Deployed Project: bit.ly/3KeU6p8

- Summary: 5-day weather forecast app
- Tools: API, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Full Stack Exercise Track | Github: bit.ly/3pyR9lh | Deployed Project: bit.ly/3KeU6p8

- Summary: Full Stack application that allows authenticated users to track their exercise progress
- Role: Frontend designer
- Tools: MongoDB, GraphQL, Express, Node, React.js, CSS

#### **Experience**

Intern | IHS pharmacy 2022-Present

- Contributed to the frontend of a Jail Management System utilizing atomic design, Typescript, and React
- Worked in an Agile, collaborative environment to implement design requirements using Figma and Azure DevOps

IT Solutions Specialist | CanopylT Solutions | Minneapolis, MN.

2018-Present

- Developed various websites for clients using Wordpress, effectively marketing individual brands to increase audience engagement.
  - o Canopyit.com, Martinmcallister.com, Poly-texdistribution.com, prairiecreek.org
- Gained CompTIA A+ certification

Office Manager | Minnesota Independent School Forum | St. Paul, MN

2017-2018

Managed registration process for all events, seminars, and meetings

Intern | Schuler Publicity | Minneapolis, MN 2016

Refactored website: schulersaid.com

## **Education**

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development | University of Minnesota

2021

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Arts in Communications | Bethel University